Product-focused full stack engineer who enjoys working on early-stage, open-ended, user-facing problems. I have five years of professional experience with Python, Django and frontend technologies. At my current role, I specialize in bootstrapping and rapidly iterating on new product ideas.

EXPERIENCE

Indeed - Software Engineer II

October 2015 - Present

- One of the founding engineers of the rapidly growing Indeed Hire team. I built the HireCentral advanced candidate management system for our team of internal staffing recruiters and other early applications for the team (chrome extension to speed up recruiter workflow, external site for clients and internal analytics tools)
- Sole developer for the Labs Edu project to build a digital resume book for colleges.
- In Summer 2017, I was one of the leads for Indeed University, acting as an engineering manager for 5 new engineers and providing mentorship for 3 new products.
- Lead developer for Scribe team, a three-month Incubator project to build a data-driven SEO tool to improve the conversion rate of job postings.
- Actively contributor to the Django Stack at Indeed (Libraries for login, RPC, monitoring, config and logging).
- Ran A/B tests, conducted usability study sessions, interviewed candidates, mentored new developers and created internal Django training workshops.

Indeed - Full Stack Software Engineer

January 2014 - October 2015

- As part of Indeed Labs, I built and launched several production web applications from the ground up using Diango.
- Developed the mobile portion of Jobsmap An application for map based job search.
- Sole developer for Job Discovery a pandora-like job search experience.
- Initial developer for Campus a mobile web app to recommend jobs for students based on their major.
- Primary maintainer for several internal apps (internal "twitter", content management system for TVs, weekly product check-in, and others).

AMD – Engineering Co-Op

January 2012 - August 2012

- Co-Op intern for the Rubymain and Unit Bin Sorter (UBS) teams.
- Worked on a ruby interface to the C++ drivers for some internal CPU validation motherboards.
- Created an eclipse plugin to generate a dynamic GUI for XML configurations managed by test engineers.

PERSONAL PROJECTS

http://fenivarughese.com

Arevel.com (2017): An excel-like visual programming language in the browser (Work in progress)

InSight (2013): Senior Design team project to automatically crop and correct pictures of whiteboard notes.

Thyself.io (2012): A personal analytics web app with natural language processing to track and analyze your daily life.

Infinite Music Machine (2011): Automatic music and poetry generation using Markov chains.

Pulsar (2008): A 2D side scrolling game I developed in High School with my friends.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: Fluent in Python, Java, JavaScript, HTML & CSS. Experience with Ruby, C, Go & Clojure.

Technologies: Proficient in Django, MySql, Bootstrap and Sass. Experience with Flask, React and Vue.js.

Tools: Proficient in Git, Linux, Vagrant. Experience with AWS and Google Cloud ecosystem.

EDUCATION

The University of Texas at Austin

December 2013